Fleeting FreedomsElderly man’s fishing net hangs in his shedThe fish he caught in his backyard stream multiplyNet use was banned; he couldn’t afford a poleJoy and sustenance gone, a tear falls from his eyeHouse Bill 875 would ban backyard farmsForcing vegetable growers to invest cashIn overpriced produce on supermarket shelvesUncle Sam flexes his muscle, makes his whip lashThe right to freely worship is endangeredAs prayer is prohibited in public schoolsGovernment intrusion invades all our livesPublic pleas are not heard by those who make rulesFreedom to choose our doctors is now threatenedSocialized medicine diminishes choiceSpeech censorship? Just ask the Smothers BrothersWho canceled their own show with a stifled voiceAs crime escalates, look to the constitutionThe NRA spends billions to protect Americans' rightsTo bear arms against oppressors while thieves laughAnd sue owners of homes invaded in the nightCan this be what our forefathers had in mindWhen they sought to escape a king’s tyranny?Our rights are being limited more each dayIn a nation spawned to promote libertyNatural disasters prelude Judgment DayEerie escalation – tsunamis, earthquakesBut perhaps when the dust finally settlesThose who survive will learn from our past mistakesGovernments will form only to preserve peaceNot to strip away rights ancestors pursuedDon’t blink!  Precious freedoms are now endangeredBy those who feel they’re elected to intrude