_Billy in                                Bunbury_                             [Illustration]------------------------------------------------------------------------                             [Illustration]------------------------------------------------------------------------                           _Billy in Bunbury_                             [Illustration]                      _Price Baking Powder Factory                      1001 Independence Boulevard                                Chicago_   COPYRIGHT, 1925; BY ROYAL BAKING POWDER CO.      PRINTED IN U.S.A.------------------------------------------------------------------------                             [Illustration]------------------------------------------------------------------------                             [Illustration]    Bunbury is a tasteful town      Beside a syrup sea,    Where sponge cake fish and waffle whales      Disport themselves in glee.    Bunbury’s streets are good to eat      Of that make no mistake,    For Bunbury’s streets are made, you know,      Of finest marble cake.------------------------------------------------------------------------                          COCOA RAISIN MUFFINS                       (_see illustration below_)    1¾ cups flour    2 tablespoons cocoa    5 tablespoons sugar    ½ teaspoon salt    ¼ teaspoon cinnamon    4 teaspoons Dr. Price’s Baking Powder    ⅔ cup raisins    ⅞ cup milk    5 tablespoons melted shorteningSift together flour, cocoa, sugar, salt, cinnamon and baking powder. Addraisins, then milk slowly to make a smooth batter. Add shortening andmix thoroughly. Put 1 tablespoon batter in each greased muffin tin andbake in moderate oven (400°) for about 20 minutes.Makes 16 muffins.                            MUFFIN SURPRISES    1 cup flour    1 cup graham flour    ¾ teaspoon salt    4 teaspoons Dr. Price’s Baking Powder    1 cup milk    1 egg    3 tablespoons sugar or molasses    4 tablespoons melted shorteningMix together dry ingredients. Add milk, beaten egg, molasses, if used,and shortening. Stir until smooth. Half fill each greased gem pan. Dropin center a stoned date, a teaspoon currant jelly, candied cherry orother fruit. Add teaspoon of batter and bake in moderate oven (375°)about 25 minutes.Makes 12 muffins.                      _All measurements are level_                             [Illustration]------------------------------------------------------------------------    Its fences are of pie crust      And its houses built of buns,    With frosted roofs and raisins      On the most important ones.    Bunbury has fine doughnut trees      Beside a chocolate fountain,    And just outside the town you’ll find      A giant layer cake mountain.    Its people are too cunning      And too sweet for any use;    There’s spry Pop Over, Johnny Cake      And dainty Charlotte Russe.    The moon’s a muffin, and the sun      A hot cake warm and mellow.    Its gentle rays make Bunbury folk      A tempting brownish yellow!    And when it snows, marshmallow      Covers everything with icing—    The houses, and the people, too,      Look even more enticing.    Bunbury’s folk oft gather round      Ye Coffee Ring, and tell    The news about young Johnny Cake—      Who’s courting Patty Shell!                             [Illustration]    Bunbury’s vaults are filled with gems      For Hun Bun, the bun boy king.    He has gems to burn (but doesn’t)      Burnt gems are not the thing.    The reason why this little town      So gay and sweet and nice is    Because each cake and cooky there      Was raised on Dr. Price’s!    Now one day as the cooky clock      In taffy tower tolled,    Flap Jack, the King’s own messenger      Into the castle rolled.    “Your Bunship!” puffed the little Jack,      “I bring surprising news!    There is a little lad near here      Too skinny for his shoes.    “He will not eat his breakfast      And he will not eat his lunch.    He’s lost his taste for baseball      And completely lost his punch!”                             [Illustration]------------------------------------------------------------------------                               FLAP JACKS                       (_see illustration below_)    1¾ cups flour    ½ teaspoon salt    3 teaspoons Dr. Price’s Baking Powder    2 eggs    1½ cups milk    1 tablespoon shorteningSift dry ingredients together; add beaten eggs, milk and meltedshortening; mix well. Bake on hot, slightly greased griddle untilbubbles appear; turn over quickly and brown other side. Serveimmediately on hot plate with plenty of butter and syrup or butter andcinnamon mixed with sugar.Makes 24 flap jacks.                          FLAP JACKS WITH RICE    1 cup boiled rice    1 cup milk    1 tablespoon melted shortening    ½ teaspoon salt    1 egg    1 cup flour    4 teaspoons Dr. Price’s Baking PowderMix rice, milk, shortening, salt and well-beaten egg; stir in flour andbaking powder which have been sifted together; mix well, adding moremilk if necessary to make a soft batter. Bake on hot, slightly greasedgriddle until bubbles appear; turn over quickly and brown other side.Serve immediately on hot plate with plenty of butter and syrup or butterand cinnamon mixed with sugar.Makes 24 flap jacks.                      _All measurements are level_                             [Illustration]------------------------------------------------------------------------    “What?” spluttered Hun Bun, pushing back      His sparkling candy crown;    “Ho! fetch my dog! Ho! fetch my cane!      I’ll catch a train to town!”    And when his cane and dog were fetched      He hopped aboard the train,    And in a way I scarce can guess      And even less explain    Arrived at little Billy’s house.      He found the boy at tea.    “Hello!” cried Hun Bun, “Howdy-do!”      And likewise, “Howdy-de!”    Then Hun Bun’s dog began to bark,      You’ve heard of him, perhaps?    He’s full of ginger and of spice      His name is Ginger Snaps.    “Why, who are you?” gasped Billy      Nearly falling in his plate.    “I’m Hun Bun!” smiled the little chap,      “The Cooky Potentate.”    “Go on and eat your supper, boy,      ’Twill make you strong and fat,    And fit to hit a punching bag      Or swing a baseball bat!”    “Not hungry” sighed the little lad      And scowled upon his meat,    And frowned into his glass of milk,      “There’s nothing fit to eat.”------------------------------------------------------------------------                               DOUGHNUTSThese doughnuts are very wholesome and excellent for children. They donot contain any shortening and should be fried very carefully in fat atjust the right temperature so that no grease will be absorbed. They canbe served plain or sprinkled with powdered sugar after they havethoroughly drained and cooled.    2 eggs    ¾ cup milk    2¾ cups flour    1 teaspoon salt    4 teaspoons Dr. Price’s Baking Powder    1 cup sugar    ½ teaspoon nutmeg or cinnamonSave ⅓ cup of measured flour for board. Beat eggs until light; add milk,then add this liquid to the dry ingredients which have been sifted welltogether. Roll out ¼ inch thick on slightly floured board and fry indeep fat (365°-375°). Drain well on unglazed paper. Sprinkle withpowdered sugar.Makes 30 doughnuts.                      _All measurements are level_                             [Illustration]------------------------------------------------------------------------    “Dear me” mused Hun Bun, while the pup      Licked Billy on the ear,    “A boy as thin as you could not      Be President I fear.”    And hopping on the table      He began to walk around,    He peered into each plate and dish,      Then even Hun Bun frowned.    And leaning on his pep’mint cane      And looking really hurt,    The bun boy King called dolefully,      “Why, where is the dessert?”    In rage he shook his candy cane,      As will such angry kings;    And roared, “It’s plain to see your fare      Lacks most essential things.    “No cakes, no cookies and no buns,      No biscuits—not a tart!    None of the things real fellows like,      Why Bill, it breaks my heart!    “It seems your mother does not know      What youngsters like to eat,    It surely is high time, I think,      That she and I should meet!”------------------------------------------------------------------------                             [Illustration]------------------------------------------------------------------------                             SUGAR COOKIES    ½ cup shortening    1½ cups sugar    ¼ cup milk    2 eggs    ½ teaspoon grated nutmeg    1 teaspoon vanilla or grated rind of 1 lemon    3 to 4 cups flour    ½ teaspoon salt    2½ teaspoons Dr. Price’s Baking PowderCream shortening and sugar together; add milk to beaten eggs and beatagain; add slowly to creamed shortening and sugar; add flavoring; add 2cups of measured flour sifted with salt, baking powder and nutmeg; addenough more flour to roll easily. Roll out thin on floured board; cutwith any fancy-shaped cooky cutter; sprinkle with granulated sugar orput a raisin or nut in the center of each. Bake about 10 minutes inmoderate oven (380°).For Chocolate Cookies put aside portion of the dough before adding allthe flour and add 2 tablespoons cocoa to each cup of cooky dough.Makes 4 dozen cookies.                      _All measurements are level_                             [Illustration]------------------------------------------------------------------------    Soon, hearing all the rumpus      Billy’s mother came to see    To whom her son was talking      And what all the noise could be.    When Hun Bun spied her, he remarked      In accents sharp and biting,    “No wonder that your boy won’t eat,      His food’s so uninviting.    “Your son wants cookies, buns and cake,      And other things that mothers make.”    Bill’s mother, looking apprehensive,      Remarked, “But cakes are so expensive.”    “Not so!” quoth Hun Bun drawing forth      A brightly colored book,    “Use Dr. Price’s Baking Powder,      Hereafter when you cook!”    Then Hun Bun gaily doffed his crown      And with a bow quite comical,    He told her, “You will find it good      And very economical.    “But now we must depart and so      We’ll bid you a good-night,    For Bill and I are going to try      To find his appetite.”------------------------------------------------------------------------                             [Illustration]------------------------------------------------------------------------                           BUTTERSCOTCH CURLS                       (_see illustration below_)    2 cups flour    4 teaspoons Dr. Price’s Baking Powder    ⅔ teaspoon salt    4 tablespoons shortening    ⅔ cup milk    Butter    Brown sugarSift dry ingredients; add shortening, mixing it in with a fork (ifliquid shortening is used, add with milk). Add milk to make a fairlysoft dough. Knead slightly and roll out ¼ inch thick. Spread well withcreamed butter and brown sugar. Roll up as for jelly roll; cut in 1-inchpieces. Stand these on end in well-buttered gem pans or in small greasedmuffin rings and bake in a hot oven (425°) about 15 minutes. Makes 12rolls or 22 if baked in small rings.                             PEANUT COOKIES    1 cup flour    ½ teaspoon salt    2 teaspoons Dr. Price’s Baking Powder    2 tablespoons shortening    1 cup chopped peanuts    ½ cup sugar    ¼ cup milk    1 egg    1 teaspoon lemon juiceSift dry ingredients together. Add melted shortening to beaten egg. Addmilk and lemon juice, and mix well with the dry ingredients to make softdough. Add peanuts; mix well and drop with teaspoon on greased pan. Bakein moderate oven (400°) about 20 minutes. This recipe makes about fourdozen small cookies and requires 1 quart of peanuts.                      _All measurements are level_                             [Illustration]------------------------------------------------------------------------    And while the puzzled lady      Grasped the cook book in surprise,    The Pup and Bill and Hun Bun      Disappeared before her eyes.    Next instant they were on a train      And hieing in a hurry    Across a golden cornbread plain      To little Hun’s Bunbury.    The engine on its lic’rice rails      Cream puffed along so fast    The pep’mint poles and chocolate cows      Went simply whizzing past!    And when they reached the station      All the tasty cakes and tarts    Were out to welcome Billy,      Bless their little sugar hearts.    The Royal Bun Band headed      By a pound cake drummer man,    Came tooting down the central street      And after it there ran    A flock of Scotch and Dutch cakes,      Twenty cookies and a roll,    While all the orange icing bells      Began to peal and toll.                             [Illustration]    Soon our Billy was no bigger      Than a Cooky Man himself;    For Hun’s magician, Devils Food,      Had changed him to an elf.    “We’re going to the circus first,”      Said Hun Bun in his ear,    “Where you can see the animals      And all the freaks, so queer.”    The little cracker animals      Cavorted ’round the tent,    Till the air was full of cracker dust      And cheers and merriment.    How Billy laughed, while Ginger barked      And Hun Bun clapped with glee;    “Come on now,” cried the mighty king      “There’s other folk to see.    “Here’s Captain Jelly Roll who drills      Our biscuit P’licemen brave,    But we don’t really need them      For good cakes like us behave.”    The more of Bunbury’s sights he saw,      The hungrier he grew,    And yet, to eat up Hun Bun’s friends      Would never, never do.                             [Illustration]------------------------------------------------------------------------                             BISCUIT TARTS    2 cups flour    3 teaspoons Dr. Price’s Baking Powder    ½ teaspoon salt    1 tablespoon sugar    1 egg    2 tablespoons shortening    ⅓ cup milkSift together flour, baking powder, salt and sugar; add well-beaten eggand melted shortening to milk and add to dry ingredients to make softdough. Roll out on floured board, ⅛ inch thick. Cut out with medium-sizebiscuit cutter which has been dipped in flour. Then taking a smallercutter, cut ½ of these rounds again. Brush the large rounds lightly withmelted butter. Then take the outer rings and lay on top of the largebuttered rounds. Put on greased baking tin. Put a teaspoon of jam ineach tart and bake in hot oven (475°) for about 10 minutes. The smallcenters can be brushed with butter and baked in the same manner andserved as little tea biscuits.Makes 10 tarts with 10 tiny biscuits.                      _All measurements are level_                             [Illustration]------------------------------------------------------------------------    While no one looked he slyly took      A piece of pie crust fence,    And next he ate a pretzel gate—      It tasted just immense!    They stopped to watch a cake walk      In the little frosted square    Where all the best and richest cakes      Were stepping it for fair.    The Scotch scones danced the Highland fling,      The Dutch cakes danced the clog,    And Hun Bun led the bun ballet      Assisted by his dog.    Young Billy felt so gay himself      He danced with Sally Lunn,    He never knew a cake walk      Was such a lot of fun.    But with every passing minute      Bill grew hungrier until    Bunbury’s king was worried!      “I’m afraid that little Bill    Will bring this cake walk to an end      And start a canni-ball,    He’ll eat my favorite subjects up      Which wouldn’t do at all.”------------------------------------------------------------------------                              PARTY CAKES    ½ cup butter    1 cup sugar    2 eggs    ⅔ cup milk    2 cups flour    ½ teaspoon salt    3 teaspoons Dr. Price’s Baking Powder    1 teaspoon vanilla extractCream butter, add sugar slowly; add beaten eggs. Sift flour, salt andbaking powder together; add a little at a time alternately with the milkto the first mixture; beat thoroughly; add flavoring and bake in greasedsmall gem pans in a hot oven (425°) about 20 minutes. Cover with plainwhite frosting.Makes 18 cakes.For chocolate cakes, add ½ cup cocoa, mixed with ½ cup cold water to theabove recipe.Makes 24 cakes.Cover with the following meringue:                             JELLY MERINGUE    White of 1 egg    ½ cup currant or other jellyPut egg white and jelly together into bowl and beat with egg beater orwire whip until stiff. Spread on tops of cakes.                      _All measurements are level_                             [Illustration]------------------------------------------------------------------------    He murmured to a tea bun,      “Though I certainly rejoice    To see he’s found his appetite,      Just order my Rolls Royce.”    Soon up it rolled, a chocolate drop      Was at the cooky wheel.    “Jump in,” cried Hun Bun, “It is time      For us to leave, I feel.    “Now you may eat the extra tire,”      (It was a doughnut brown)    “Oh, thank you, Hun,” cried Billy,      As they sped from Bunbury town.    They reached home very quickly      By the magic route they took,    And there they found Bill’s mother      Absorbed in Hun Bun’s book.    “Here’s Billy,” shouted Hun Bun,      “With an appetite so hearty    He gobbled up a fence and gate      And nearly ate the party!”    “The things I saw all looked so good      I longed to eat my fill,    Oh, mother, how I wish that you      Could make me some,” cried Bill.    “I never could,” she started,      But this speech was not allowed her,    For Hun Bun cried, “You can if you      Use Price’s Baking Powder!”------------------------------------------------------------------------                             [Illustration]------------------------------------------------------------------------                             BIRTHDAY CAKE    1 cup butter    1½ cups sugar    1 teaspoon vanilla extract    1 teaspoon lemon extract    5 eggs    ⅓ cup milk    2½ cups pastry flour    2 teaspoons Dr. Price’s Baking PowderCream butter thoroughly; beat in sugar, a little at a time. Addflavoring and yolks of eggs beaten until pale yellow. Add milk, beatingin a little at a time. Beat egg whites until light. Sift flour withbaking powder three times. Add alternately small portions of egg whitesand flour and stir mixture until light and fluffy. Bake in greased loafpan in moderate oven (350°) about one hour. Cover with followingornamental frosting:    1½ cups granulated sugar    ½ cup water    2 egg whites    ⅛ teaspoon salt    1 teaspoon flavoring extract, half lemon, half vanillaBoil sugar and water, without stirring until syrup spins a thread(238°); add slowly to beaten egg whites; add salt and flavoring; beatuntil smooth and stiff enough to spread. Put over boiling water,stirring continually until icing grates slightly on bowl. Spread on topand sides of cake.                      _All measurements are level_                             [Illustration]------------------------------------------------------------------------    So saying, Hun gave her a can      Of bright and sunny yellow.    “With this you easily can make      Good things for this young fellow.    “And Madam, ’stead of coaxing      Boys and girls to eat, ’tis wiser    To add a cake or cooky      As a little appetizer!”    From the day that he met Hun Bun      Little Bill began to gain.    His appetite’s tremendous      And the reason’s very plain.    His mother makes him good things      Of which he eats his fill,    For everything she puts in them      Is good for little Bill.    Dr. Price’s Baking Powder      And King Hun Bun’s wondrous book    Have made of Billy’s mother      An exceedingly good cook.    He eats his lunch and breakfast      Each meal he finds a treat.    The other fellows watch their step      When Bill comes down the street.    Cakes like he met in Bunbury      His mother makes him now    And if YOU want some too, this book      Will tell YOUR MOTHER how!